No matter what happens, you should never
fire the first 15 engineers in the
company. This is Ryan. He grew from a
frontline manager at Facebook to a
senior director at Snapchat in 3 years
and shared everything he learned along
the way.
>> A very critical cultural philosophy I
learned from Facebook is that everyone
who work on engineering need to be
technical.
>> At Snapchat, he shared interesting
learnings working with the founder and
CEO. Evan have a really high bar for
performance and it reminds me Steve
Jobs.
>> Part [snorts] of his growth was from job
hopping to a director role at Square and
then you were thrust into a director
role. What were the biggest gaps that
you [music] saw?
>> There's a lot of gaps but the biggest
gap I saw.
>> Here's the full episode. [music]
I'd like to go into one of the first
legs of your career which is when you
joined Facebook. What is the story
behind you joining Facebook? Yeah. So I
think that's an interesting story. My
career path is a little bit
nontraditional. I was a PhD. I used to
be a research world for more than eight
years. So and because after I graduate,
I spent five years in PhD program and
then I spent another three years in IBM
as a research scientist mostly focused
on computer vision and machine learning,
right?
And then I start to realize um
industrial research model like IBM
research or Microsoft research with this
kind of 50% mix between research and
engineerings it's probably not going to
be sustainable.
I have to choose either 100% on research
or 100% on engineering one way or the
others. So that's why that was back in
the year of like 2009 I started to
reflect on that. Then I start to
question myself okay which path I should
go. There are three paths in front of
me. One is that I can be a faculty in
some school. In fact I do an interview
with some top school at that time or I
can be a quant developer or quant trader
in a financial engineering firm. I also
have offers from some of the top
quantitative trading firms or I go to a
software engineering company like
Facebook. So when I was thinking deeper
first I want to be software engineers. I
think that's the way that you can
creating something that was influence
more people than just doing trading.
The second thing is that I want to go to
a places that can make engineering to be
the first class citizens. I think in the
financial world engineering is always a
second class. It's not a first class. I
can be a faculty but being faculty I
think the impact is smaller because you
can only impact the scale of a school or
maybe the community but not the entire
world. So that's why that was the years
I make up my minds that I want to be in
the software engineering world and then
if I want to be a software engineering
ro I want to join a company that are
fast growing and have the potentials to
influence a lot of people and I think
Facebook it is the one that fits with my
criteria. So that's why I'm lucky enough
to be part of a Facebook during the fast
growing years like in the early 29th. So
I think at Facebook you you transitioned
into management and I think the things
in your career that I'm most interested
in is at the subsequent two companies at
Square and at Snapchat. Your career had
explosive growth because at Square I saw
you were there for a little over a year
and you went from a frontline manager to
a director. Your team was around 40 plus
engineers. So I'm kind of curious to dig
into how you got that opportunity and
how that growth came.
>> Yeah, I'll be very transparent here. In
fact, like when I joined Square, I was
taking a director offer to join the
square.
>> Oh, okay. So you signed up with a team
that was uh already director size.
>> Exactly. Yeah. So and of course Square
is a smaller company. So that's why they
are willing to give me the opportunity
to perform at a director level. after I
joined the company um when I started the
team it's about 25 people and then I
grow the teams into 50 plus people in a
years before I left the company so um I
I indeed spend a lot of time to grow the
machine learning teams and data science
infrastructure teams like back in square
I think it's actually a very helpful
exercise but one thing I do have to say
that and in fact this is one of the the
lesson learned for myself is that I do
things like my transitions from managers
to director teach me a lot of things. I
start to learn a lot about the
difference between line managers and
directors and why they call it
directors.
So because director is about directing
instead of managings. So it really
opened my mind about what's the right
way to managing managers instead of
managing IC's. So you need to use a
completely different philosophy to do
that and it takes me some time to adjust
to it but after this exercise I think
I've become a better managers at a
different level.
>> Yeah. I'm curious because you your
career grew so quickly that I wonder if
there were any skill gaps. You were you
went from a frontline manager and then
you were thrust into a director role. Um
what were the biggest gaps that you saw?
>> Yep. So the there's a lot of gaps but
the biggest gap I saw it's about back to
the word directing when I first step
into the director role I actually don't
understand the difference between
director versus managers but when I
start to practice it I start to realize
like managing and managers require
different set of skill because like
typically the line managers are the one
that knows the detail the best unlike my
Facebook experience I grow from IC to
become a managers then I'm the one in
the teams knows most of the details. So
that's why I continue I can continue to
use that as the anchor points to
managing other people because almost
most the other people in my teams join
after me. So that's why I'm the senior
people in the rooms but you start to go
to a new environment you become the more
junior people in the company but you
actually leading the more senior people
in the in their tenurs of the company.
they are more senior and but you are
leading them and also they know more
details than you then what's the right
way for me being a director positions to
actually provide my values to those
people that's the most interesting part
of it if because like I don't think I do
well in the first half a year and once I
don't do well they may start to just
feel like okay why do I actually need
this layer at all because I'm not adding
any values to their their daily life. So
and that was the time I start to reflect
is that if I'm becoming a middle layers
between them and the higher level
executive what are the value that I
should bring in for the organizations.
So I think like what you end up landing
on it will be about like high level
thinking about strategical directions
about like the possibility that you can
help to collect resource across
different department about like solving
the most difficult problem for the
organizations. It's all about those kind
of a directions and that's why it speak
to the difference between directing and
managing. So it's no longer simply about
managing people anymore. It's about
directing an organizations towards to a
better positions in the futures. So
essentially it means you need to operate
at a very different level than what it
used to be. So it takes takes me some
time to understand it. So the thing that
took you from maybe underperforming
initially to fitting into the director
role was you stepped away from directly
managing people and you thought more
strategically about the the group and
that you were leading. Yeah. So that's
totally the case and also like put some
more salt around what does your direct
report was looking for from you. So, and
there's some there's definitely a
reasons why the original leader choose
not to promote any of the existing
leader into my role. Instead, they
choose to hire another person's into
that role. There must be a reason behind
that. And this means that there is must
be an area for improvement for them. as
a leader myself then I need to make it
clear and then need to understand that
okay what I can do to help to grow that
persons from their current levels to the
next level what's the missing pieces
like what other thing I can help them so
and when I start to understand that that
going back to my analogy of like
comparing management to psychological
doctors right so you start to understand
what they are looking for and then you I
will align my work towards that and once
you start to do that then you start to
get more respect from those people
because they understand that you are
here to help them to grow to the next
level. So yeah I think that's that's
sort of a turning point for my director
career. I can imagine that there's a
psychological effect here if someone
gets hired a level above you. You know
maybe these people were hoping for that.
Did you deal with any incidents like
that and how do you how do you handle
that kind of situation?
>> So first yeah I definitely dealt with
that because it's a it's a human nature
things everyone want to get promoted and
everyone will questions why they are not
the one that could promote it. So that's
why the way to handle that is to really
help them to understand that with me
coming in it's actually much better
situation for them in terms of their
career instead of a negative
and in that cases you need to find a
common ground between you and your
direct report. So you are not a blocker
for their career instead but you are
actually a promoter for their career.
And this is actually one thing I only
realized half years after I become the
director to be honest. So but after I do
that I think I'm doing much better in my
following career in the future is that
every single time when I go to a new
places the number one thing I would do
is to build a trust layer and this is a
place I really recommend a book called
the five dysfunctions of a teams. I
think that book taught me a lot also. I
mean basically the book one of the key
narrative for that book it's about um
the most foundational layer for a
successful team it is trust everything
building on top of trust so that's the
first things I would do is to build up a
trust relationships with that person's
so he need to trust me that I'm here to
help him then I need to start to execute
a few things to make him understand that
so and also you need to help him to
unblock some of the things that he
cannot unblock himself. That also shows
the value of you being an upper
management to help your people. So I
think that become more and more
important things like so for for
building a successful teams. You
mentioned that you were hired in as a
director. So that makes me think about
let's say you are a really ambitious
manager and you're thinking about how
can you grow and level and you know
there's the approach of staying
somewhere trying to get promoted and
then there's also job hopping. Do you
think that job hopping is kind of the
best way to to jump up tiers as a
manager?
>> I never think about job hopping is the
best way to jump up to the managers.
Yeah. In fact, even when I talk about
Facebook, a lot of my OT team members
are already in a very high level. Some
of my friends are already VP of
engineering in Facebook. So that's why I
don't think job hopping is the always
the the only way or the right way to do
it. But I can speak to like why I choose
to do that. My philosophy is about
northstar. I always have a northstar
goal in my mind is that I want to become
a CTO at some point for a AI company.
>> You did it.
>> So [laughter]
thank you. Yeah. So that that that has
been a no struggle even like after I get
my PhD degree for m for machine
learning. I have been imagining a well
at some point that AI can become a
business by itself. But when I when I
graduated, the world is not like that. I
mean AI is just always amplifiers.
It's just like a component in a bigger
company who can make the business
better. That's interesting, but that's
not the most interesting part of it. So
that's why when I start to make up my
mind that this is my northstar goal,
then I want to make a plan out of it. My
plan is that if I want to become a CTO,
I have a lot of a weak link for that.
Especially when I coming after my
research career, I know from a being a
research scientist to be a CTO, there's
a lot of gap. So I recognize my gap.
It's about not understanding the
industry, how industry operate, don't
understanding infrastructure and back
end, don't understand front end than
product and don't understand like many
other things. So that's why I need to
choose my career to help me to fill in
those gap step by step. And in fact,
here's a story. Before I joined
Snapchat, I'm always a data and machine
learning person. All of my position was
related to data and machine learning.
And when I joined Snapchat, there are
two option in front of me. Either I
choose to become the director of data or
I choose to become director of camera,
which is the first page of Snapchat.
I intentionally choose to become the
director of camera and I need to learn
about iOS and Android programming from
scratch. I literally spend like two
months learn about iOS programming.
Again, I think this is a very
unconventional choices because I believe
most people would just like go with
director of data because that's the
that's most comfortable selection you
can make.
But my northstar is trying to become a
CTO. I think in order to become a CTO, I
need to understand product. I need to
understand working with product managers
and product designer and arguably if you
just like follow your traditional career
progression within a company it's really
hard to do that it's really hard to jump
from a backend team to a more product
facing teams at that point so I think
that I actually take that as a very
great opportunity to challenge myself to
run something difference and to inch
towards towards my what I'm looking for
at the end so and I'm glad Yeah, make
that choice. In fact, the first two
years in Snapchat is probably one of the
happiest periods for my career because I
really enjoy that period. I'm learning
new things. I find that myself was
developing my knowledge base every
single day and
and I that's the reasons why I was like
choosing different things at different
stage of my career. you worked in very
different domains in as an engineering
leader and I was curious how much do the
details of the teams that you manage
matter. This is a very critical cultural
philosophy I learned from Facebook is
that everyone who work on engineering
need to be technical. I still remember
the times that like Facebook have this
six weeks boot camp process. I don't
know whether they still have it right
now. So, but when back in times,
everyone need to go into the six week
boot camp process before they can choose
a teams, right? And I remember there's a
uh a VP level hires sitting right next
to me and she's just like doing the same
thing as what I was doing like finding
bugs, fixing bugs, writing poll
requests. She was doing that for six
week. That actually shocks me because I
come from IBM like IBM's VP never code
anymore. I mean, I don't even they
probably only write PBTs at the end, I
think. But this is one things that was
deeply planning in my heart afterwards
is that I believe being technical being
detail driven it's a very critical
things for us success in the futures and
that's also part of the reasons why I
also love to get into detail these days.
So I write I still write codes I still
review codes like right now I at least
write two or three porest every single
week. I'm also the kind of person I'm
not really good at speaking up if I
don't know the details. I want to make
sure that I understand the details so
that I know I'm not making things so so
that I can make the best strategic
decisions for the teams. How how do you
find that balance though? Because even
as an IC there is some balance where you
start to you know lower leverage tasks
you start offloading them to scale
yourself and you only take on the very
critical things. I can't even imagine
like as a CTO or director what even
detailed work is worth picking up. I
think the the best way to scale this is
to always going back to your first
principle. So at the beginning of every
single week I will ask myself what are
the top three things I need to achieve
only focus on those top three things and
then every everything else is less
important. So and sometimes one of those
top three things will be development
getting the details. So I think that's
very critical part of it. It's not. So
that's why I'm not saying that every
single week you need to do the same
things, but every single week you need
to have a themes for your work and you
naturally understand how each themes is
going to bring the best bang for the
bucks for your north star goal. So
that's why you keep recalibrating
yourself towards it. And I think this is
the best way to scale because like at
the end every every every people only
have eight hour working time or maybe 10
or 12 working time every single day but
that's it. So you you can't have more. I
think the best people not really just
like spending more time but they're
really good at allocating their time and
by understand the priority of each
directions and spend the right time at
each priorities. I understand that
Snapchat is in Los Angeles which is you
know very different from Silicon Valley.
I'm curious did you notice a big
difference in the cultures in LA versus
Silicon Valley? Yeah. So I think
specific for Snapchat the culture is
actually very similar to Bay Area
company and in fact when I joined
Snapchat I found it surprisingly similar
to Facebook's culture. It's all it's a
moving fast places break things done is
better than perfect. I all those things
apply to both Facebook and Snapchat and
partly because a lot of early people
coming from Snapchat or working in
Snapchat they come from Bay Area or
Seattle. So that's why like Snapchat has
built a culture very similar to that.
But broadly speaking I think LA is a way
more diverse space than Silicon Valley.
I still remember like when I was living
in Bay Area, I lived there for five, six
years. Whenever I go to an event or a
dinners like you can find that like most
of the topic people talk about on the
dinner table tech stock startups the
topic are almost always the same. So
because that's a that bring Bay Area to
fame but also means that a lot of people
was working on the same things. But in
Los Angeles you get very different wipe.
you get access to a lot of different
kind of people. For example, um in my
neighborhoods, one of my neighbor it's a
it's a doctor. It's a medical doctor and
another neighbor it's actually a
cryptographer for Michael Jackson's. I
think I can never get access to those
kind of people when I was back in San
Francisco. It really help you to broaden
your views outside Silicon Valley. you
start to understand that oh it turns out
a lot of our people a lot of our users
are not just techie are not just AI
people instead there's a lot of common
persons who can still benefit from your
product and it help you to put yourself
into their shoes to understand like how
your product should be built in their
cases I saw your team grew to the size
of 250 engineers at Snapchat what drove
grow that growth.
>> I think we grow that organically in the
sense that like Snapchat become a bigger
company over times. I remember when I
first joined Snapchat, the whole company
only have 100 people. I'm probably the
100th employees and Snapchat grow into
about 3,000 employee in two years. So
that's why like my team size also grew
together with that overall company
growth. At the same time, of course,
there's a lot of efforts putting into
recruiting. Like really shout out to the
recruiting teams. I mean, a lot of
efforts like to our interviewers for
making it happens. But overall, I think
like for a size of a company that worth
like tens of billion dollar, I think
that's a reasonable size of a company
that you can you want to build at that
time. We do learn a lot from that
process. And this is what I always call
a painful period for fast growing. You
will quickly realize the cultures that
you want for a 100 people company is
going to be very different from a
culture for 3,000 people company. You
will see a lot of different sort of a
culture start to clash with each other
and in a good way. So that's why every
single time when you double your team,
you almost like you're building a new
company at that time. And this is the
period that the leadership has to be
very resilient and we need to be very
adaptive to the new environment just
cannot always just hold on to one thing
to say okay I'm not going to change that
like in fact that's different because we
are building a very new company now we
are very different company we need you
use new way to think about the problems
so yeah but that also really helped me
to grow to seeing how you can grow a
much smaller team to a much bigger team
what kind of a process has you know go
through to make it happen.
>> As a senior director at Snapchat, I
imagine you might have had some
proximity to Evan Spiegel. Do you have
any stories working with him and what
made him effective?
>> We do have direct access to Evan. So in
fact um I work pretty closely with Evans
like for a few projects. I really like
Evan as a leaders. So and in fact the
two things really strike my mind like
when you work with Evans first Evan have
a really high bar for performance.
So and his bar is even at the pixel
level and it reminds me of Steve Jobs.
So and then basically for example in our
product review if we show him a demo he
will actually point out pixel level
issues and ask us to fix. So that's why
sometimes I would say that okay if we're
building a demo we say you need to build
a ready demo not a normal demo
but that really helped him to be very
successful in terms of like building a
great product that's what he's really
good at second thing is that I think he
really care about personal connections
especially with the engineers like he
really keep his promise and uh he
appreciate the value of engineerings so
one thing I remember very clearly is
that like he actually told one of our
leader is that no matter what happens,
you should never fire the first 15
engineers in the company because they
are the founding member for the company.
Snapchat was like start in a in a place
called a blue house. It's actually very
small house uh back in Venice Beach and
then because the company is growing
expanding very quickly. So that's why
they they no longer working in their
small places. But after four years, I
think it's 2017, like everyone bought
their house back and then he start
hosting the ball meeting back in their
house.
So you can see he's really deeply care
about this kind of connections, this
like personal relationships. And that
also probably explain why he was trying
to build Snapchat and reach inherently
it is a a tool that help people to build
like more intimate connections and and
creating like conversation with each
other. So yeah, he's a he's a really
good person for that.
>> You know, after you left Snapchat, I saw
that you went to a series of startups
and now that you explained that your
your overarching northstar, everything's
now making sense. So now at this point
it looks like you're starting to take on
uh larger leadership roles at smaller
and smaller companies. I'm kind of
curious how does the recruiting work at
these levels?
>> Yeah, I have to be honest on this one.
Maybe bragging a little bit but I never
look for a new job myself. I never look
for new jobs proactively at least. So it
all it's all coming inbound like from
either personal connections or like some
recruiter outreach. And in most of the
cases I I would prefer to go to a places
that I actually have personal connection
with because this is this is my
fundamental belief. My fundamental
belief is that no matter where I'm going
to I'm going to go through upcycle and
down cycle. There will be a period the
company do well and there will be a
period the company will not do well. And
this is true for almost all company I've
been to like Facebook and Square,
Snapchat and like things like that,
right? So I want to be not only I can
grow with the company during the upcycle
but I also want to grow with the company
during the down cycle but in order to go
through a down cycle I want to work with
persons that I like and I can think a
lot with them so that we can all working
together as a team to go through that
and that's why I really feel like
personal connection is a big part of it
for that decisions and the reality is
that like it's It's a good time for
engineerings in the sense that like I
keep getting recruiting email almost
every single week like for different
positions but I ignore majority of those
email but if it's a things come through
my personal connections I value it way
more I find that that actually will be
the more interesting part that can help
me to excel in the long term so that's
why yeah this is basically my story yeah
overall All I think all that also speak
to the fact that building a professional
network
connections early and it's a very useful
exercise. So because you never know this
kind of opportunity when this kind of
opportunity will come but you want to
capture the opportunity when it arrive.
How do you compare the roles that you
that come your way? Because when you're
in a wellestablished ladder, you know,
you're a director, a director role comes
and you kind of decide on some but let's
say you're you're CTO of a certain
company and you want to consider another
leadership role at another smaller
company. Do you is it number of people
working there? Is it valuations? What
how do you make those calls?
>> To be honest, I never take those two
things into account. The valuations are
the people report to me. I actually want
less people to report to me right now.
So, but it's all anchor against my
northstar goal. Yeah. So, maybe I bring
that back before, but I want to bring
this back to that also. I want to
understand is that choice actually
helped me to move closer to what I want
to do. I start to feel like this is
getting more and more important in my
career because the the one things I
gradually realized like when I was
spending more time in the industry
I start to realize levels and titles
those are the things the company give
that to you it's not your things and as
an example my original I mean I would
say my my role model uh 10 years ago was
like senior people in a company like
executive VP in a company, senior VP in
a company. That was my role model. But I
also start to realize when they left the
company, you will immediately hear much
less about them externally. I'm not
saying that they are not doing
meaningful work, but you seeing you're
hearing less from them externally and
people are still calling them XVP of
some things. I start to realize, okay,
yeah, the title it's about the company,
it's not about you. So people are not
going to say okay you did this things
instead they will say the company did
these things and the more I think about
it the more I feel like okay maybe this
is not what actually interest to me
instead I want people to remember myself
as someone who actually built this
product that can make their life better
I feel like that's actually way more
fulfilling for myself so that's why like
a lot of my decision end up anchoring
towards that direction so you can see
it's less about number of people I
manage I don't care. It's less about
like the valuation of a company. I don't
care. I care more about am I doing
something that are impactful right now.
In fact, I literally joking to my
friends yesterday is that I'm waiting
for the times that two people can make a
$1 billion company and it's probably
going to come in pretty soon and you may
not have any direct report at that time
and that's totally okay because I'm
making a lot of impact out of it. So
that's actually what I want to anchor
towards when we're trying to hire good
talent. The number one thing I want to
do is to be very honest and transparent
to them why they should join hun and
they should not join hun. So for anyone
who join hent I want them to believe
that we can grow into a much bigger
company. Yeah. And also want them to
believe there's like only 1% chance we
can do that. But they have to believe in
that because this will be a tough cycle
and this will not be always smooth. This
will you have a lot of bump to get
there. So but I think I want people to
feel feel excited about being part of it
to go through this kind of up and down
to get there. So and I think style is
only good for that kind of people. It's
interesting that you you want them to
know that it's it's a very low chance of
success. Why would you sell that to the
candidate? I believe that's the winning
strategies. I always [snorts] believe in
the power of being honest and
transparent. So, it's much better off
they know that upfront and they
intentionally make their choices to join
us so that they won't leave the company
when they start to see like some slight
difficulty. I also believe that like
when you go to a battlefield with the
soldiers, you want all soldiers to be
able to understand the difficulty
they're going to face, but they are
pumper for it. They're not going to
scare by that. This is the kind of
preparations we want to get after. So at
the end, I'm not going to hire the
entire world of the engineers, but I
want to sift out 5% or the 1% of people
who really truly want to go with us
along this journey. And hopefully we can
get that but we will do that with with
like all the transparencies that we we
we we can give that to them. Coming to
the end of the conversation, I want to
go over some, you know, career
reflections. And, you know, one of the
first things that I think was
interesting to me about your career is
you defined a north star on that you
wanted to be a CTO at a AI first um
company and that kind of guided all of
your decisions. Whereas I see a lot of
other people their career strategy is I
want to become you know as high as I can
go or I want to make as much money as I
can or something like that. What's the
pro and con of designing your your
career um like you did as opposed to
this external factors that a lot of
people design their careers around.
>> First I think there's no right or wrong
for any of the criteria you just
mentioned. In fact, I will even consider
my career decision is a little bit
non-conventional because for example, uh
most of my friends back in IBM research,
they would never choose to go to
Facebook as a smaller company at that
time. It's like the most common choices
they're going to choose is go to a
school to be a faculty or go to another
industrial research lab to be another
research scientist. And I think they can
do really well also at that time. So
that's why I don't think there's a right
or wrong at this one. But it's really
about like what you as a persons want to
do and I one thing I believe is that
everyone is different and everyone was
motiving
process are very important and my
criteria will be let's say 15 years
later if I choose to retire at that time
if I look back at my career am I feel
regret for anything am I feel regret of
not doing this things. If I would feel
regret, I rather do it now. So, and then
I know that I will feel regret if I
never do an AI company
and make that happens. I'll probably
feel regret. So, that's why I rather do
it now in this moment. When it comes to
regrets, uh is there anything that you
feel like you you wish you changed along
your career path that others could learn
from?
>> This is a very good questions. Yeah,
there's a lot of things I can change and
I would say that in fact my career
progression is not the smoothest
progressions. So maybe back to my very
first questions if you ask me whether I
would choose PhD or not. If I know that
I'm going to software engineering, I'm
probably not going to choose that. But
it doesn't really means that I did not
learn anything from my P get anything
out of it. But it is not the most like
smoothest path that you can get. So and
then but there's no such things in the
world that I can have a magic wand to
predict what's going to happen in the
next 10 years and to be honest I cannot
even predict what AI is going to happens
in the next three months. So [snorts]
that's why I think the most important
thing I realized is never take anything
for granted. Always learn to adapt.
Always be able to like learn about the
new knowledge as quickly as possible and
adapt yourself. And if you have a
short-term setback, for example, while
you are why I'm transitioning from
research world into a engineering world
or transition from a line managers to a
director, don't be disappointed. This is
just a moment for adjustment and learn
how to adjust and you'll be a better
self afterwards. I think a lot of your
like when I look at your career, a lot
of your growth, if I were to plot it, it
really kind of took off when you got the
Square director offer and then also when
you went to Snapchat and Snapchat grew a
ton and um you know some some of that
growth is opportunity and it seems you
know there's a Snapchat could have also
went down too but you you had the right
situation, the right market um for you
to have the career growth that you had
at that time. I'm kind of curious how
much of u manager career growth do you
see is uh situational and how much of it
is something you can control uh as
you're looking forward by making the
right decisions. The more I progress in
my career, the more I realize I cannot
control too many things particular for
manager positions because manager
position by its nature is heavily
constrained by organization structure
and organization need. These are the
things that relate to overall company
strategies not related to yourself. So
that's why like the only thing you can
do is to do the best in the positions
that you have and then everything else
will be a lagging indicators. And the
one things that I also realized is that
the happiest time in my career is that
when I start to realize this is that
don't don't aim for promotions. Don't
make promotions to be the objective of
your work. If you start to do that,
you're going to feel really painful
because there's one exercise I sometimes
see from the people I I I mentor is that
they will just like look at every single
bullet points of the next level. They
start to check, okay, do I meet this? Do
I do? Oh, okay. I meet everything. Now
that I'm talking to managers, okay, when
can I get next promotions? That's very
wrong. Don't do that. Because when you
start to get into that mindset, you
start to counting your your happiness or
your career growth towards some things
that you don't have fully full control
on. In fact, you think about things
reversely. Control the things that you
can control, which is making impact for
your current positions and drive your
career towards a positions that you love
in the long terms and don't make
yourself feel regrettable at that time.
That's the things you can control.
controlled it. Everything else will be a
lagging indicators. If you're lucky, you
get the promotions. If you're not lucky,
don't worry about it. Sometime something
will come afterwards. You can even found
your own company at some points and you
may be even richer at that time. Always
focus on things that you can control. I
think that's the that's how you can
become happier in your career. I think
and then the last question I'd like to
ask is um if you could give yourself
some advice right when you had graduated
from the PhD program knowing everything
you know in your career what advice
would you give yourself?
>> You don't need to always follow the cal
conventional wisdom and everyone is
unique and everyone can choose the past
they want. As another anecdotal example
like before I choose CMU as a school I
actually have a few other offers like
Princeton or Cornell and those school
and my dad later asked me okay why you
are not going to Princeton because
Princeton is like much more well-known
school back in China I did not listen to
his advice and I think it's the right
call because CMU is much better places
for computer science but that's a
conventional wisdom so you don't need to
always follow and as another example I
And I sort of mentioned that a little
bit is that there's almost no one in the
research community will consider joining
a small company like Facebook like fair
was created back in like 2014 but 2009
five years earlier it's very difficult
for a researchers to completely reset
like his research career and join a
software engineering company like that.
But I don't think that will apply to me.
I would just want to try something new
and once I know what's a northstar that
I'm aiming for then I'm going to apply
the strategies behind that and go
towards it. I think this will be a more
difficult path to be honest. It's like
less comfortable.
But I also believe that only the people
who can think differently early they can
see the new opportunity that no one else
can see. That will increase your chance
to win the game at the end. Well, thank
you so much, Rome, for your time. Um,
really appreciate you sharing your
career story with everyone. And now, if
you want, um, maybe you could talk about
Hey Jen and why it's a good place to
work. I think there's a lot of, um,
software engineers in the audience that
might be interested.
>> Totally. Yeah. So, Hen is um, allin-one
video generation platforms. Our idea is
very simple. We want everyone can be
able to access to video generation and
visual storytellings. We have a I would
consider as the top tier technical stack
on human centric video generations and
we can build the best hyperrealistic
avatar for people and compared with many
other video generation platforms we are
really differentiating on quality
consistency and controllability and also
another thing is that most of the other
people want to focus on creative
professional like movie makers Hollywood
stuff We really want to focus on content
professionals like marketers,
salespersons and everyday corporate
persons like us. We really want to
enable not just the Hollywood people can
make video. We want to enable everyone
to make videos at any source at any
languages at all times. So my dream is
very simple. I want to make camera
obsolete. I want to make the
storytelling accessible to everyone
without a camera. So that's what we are
hoping for.
>> Yeah. Maybe one day I won't need to be
in front of the camera for the podcast.
I can just give a script to one of your
models.
>> I'm literally thinking about same
things. Maybe in the future we just have
two literally interactive avatar talking
to each other. We can finish our podcast
in that way.
>> Thanks for listening to the podcast. I
don't sell anything or do sponsorships,
but if you want to help out with the
podcast, you can support by engaging
with the content on YouTube or on
Spotify. If you want to drop a review,
that'll be super helpful. And if there's
any guests that you want to bring on to,
please let me know. I feel like sourcing
very senior IC's, there's no wellstudied
list out there on Google that I can just
search this up. So, if there's someone
in your org or at your company who you
really look up to and you want to hear
their career story, let me know and I'll
reach out to